<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<records path="tim.xml">
  <record bib="3668927">
    <title>[Lectures on surgery].</title>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Binder's title; though lettered Volume 1, 1829, contents are complete.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">The manuscript, written in ink on paper and bound in cloth with quarter leather, is not in Brodie's hand and does not correspond with his printed "Lectures" [1846 or 1852] or with his "Works" [1865]. It was purchased by Yale Med from Walford catalog 41 in April, 1962.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Watermarked 1828.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">The lectures (39 in number, with Introduction and Index) were delivered to students in London during 1829. They concern surgery and kindred subject matter.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3668932">
    <title>Surgery and diary / Sewall Brown's.</title>
    <note type="a" review="n" reviewer="wn">Cover title.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in brown ink on paper, was sent by Richard Wheatland to John Fulton in February, 1933. Dr. Fulton later donated it to the Yale Medical Historical Library. Entries include medical and accounting data.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3668983">
    <title>Partielle Differentialgleichungen; Anwendungen der Abel'schen Functionen; Infinitesimalgeometrie; Bestimmte Integration / [vorgetragen von Prof. Christoffel], 1885-1886.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Lecture notes taken by Lehmann during four mathematics classes taught by Professor Christoffel at Strassburg during the 1885-1886 school session.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3669045">
    <title>Report of the Committee concerning the Hemlock Gum agreeable to the following vote of the Strafford District of the New Hampshire Medical Society : read before the Stafford District of the New Hampshire Medical Society,  Feb'y.11, 1818.</title>
    <note type="a" review="n" reviewer="wn">Caption title.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Report, written Jan. 10, 1818 in ink on paper, acquired by Dr. Cushing in 1935; source not specified.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3669062">
    <title>Robert Duer's receipt book, 10th of July, 1812 : book 10.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Likely Duer's pharmacy/materia medica class notes, as he graduated from the University of Pennsylvania in 1814.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in brown ink on paper, was purchased by Yale Med in May, 1950 from Whitlock (book seller of New Haven, Conn.). Title from material written inside front cover.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Inside front cover: "Robert Duer's Book the 10th of July 1812" ; inside back cover: "Robert Duer's book 1813."</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3669075">
    <title>Daybook.</title>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in black ink on lined paper, was purchased by Yale Med from Everett Hale Whitlock in November, 1943.</note>
    <note type="a" review="n" reviewer="wn">Binder's title.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3669791">
    <title>Ḥāshiyat Tahdhīb Jānqarī. -- [17--?].</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Mach gives title as: Ḥāshiyah ʻalá Ḥāshiyat Mīr Abī al-Fatḥ.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, paper-covered, with flap.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Occasional glosses.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3669929">
    <title>Kifāyat al-ghulām fī iʻrāb al-kalām. -- [15--?].</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Also known as: al-Alfīyah.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, paper-covered, with flap.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">With: 1 other title.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670378">
    <title>Excerpta ex diariis : mélanges de médecine et de chirurgie.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Entries are dated 1838-1843 and include an index on the final 23 pages.</note>
    <note type="ow" review="n" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in black ink on pale blue paper and bound in contemporary boards by a Russian(?) physician, is chiefly in Latin but includes some French and German.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Purchased by Yale Medical Library from Thiebaud (Paris book seller) catalog 85 in 1963.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670397">
    <title>[Manuscrits d'un chirurgien russe ou tchèque].</title>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in ink and bound into seven volumes with decorative full cloth boards, was purchased by Yale Med from Thiébaud (Paris book dealer) in December, 1963. Dealer unable to identify the author; but his extensive descriptive commentary is pasted onto inside of back cover of volume one.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Manuscript of a Russian or Czech surgeon on various subjects, with some entries dated from 1833 to 1842.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670439">
    <title>Physiology : lectures on the physical conditions of the tissues of the human body as applied to the explanation of vital phenomena : delivered at the College of France, 1834 / by F. Magendie, Professor of Physiology and Medicine, 1834.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Notes taken down by Robert Sewell, with the 7 p. at end titled "Index."</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, neatly written in English and bound in quarter leather, includes 24 lectures; it was purchased by Yale Med in 1958.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670491">
    <title>Sharḥ al-ʻArūḍ al-Andalusī. -- 1728.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Variant title in manuscript: Sharḥ mushkilāt al-mukhtaṣar fī ʻilm al-ʻarūḍ.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, in brown, with flap.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Followed by 3 pages (25 verso-26), untitled and ending abruptly, unrelated to primary text.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">With: 6 other titles.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670518">
    <title>Receipes for takeing of cemicals, 1850.</title>
    <note type="a" review="n" reviewer="wn">Caption title.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Page 3 has small label pasted on, reading: "Salts of gold, Meade Brothers, Importers, No. 233 Broadway, N.Y." The brothers established that location in 1850, hence the dating of the document.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Recipes for mixing chemicals.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">The name D. F. [or G.?] Kellogs, Utica, New York, is inscribed within.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in ink on first five pages of a 32 page booklet (remainder is blank), includes bookplate of Yale University Library dated 1942.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670544">
    <title>Note-book of experiments and observations on anatomy and physiology / George Gulliver, January 1839.</title>
    <note type="ao" review="n" reviewer="wn">Manuscript notebook bound in quarter leather, written in black ink on unlined paper, kept by Gulliver over a period of years, the last one seeming to be 1874; titled from author's inscription inside front cover.</note>
    <note type="ow" review="n" reviewer="wn">Some pages are blank, some have extra leaves inserted; there is an index on the final page.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Inserted are several letters addressed to the author from John Davy and one from Thomas Hodgkin; also an "Obituary notice" of Gulliver written in his own hand.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Includes much of his original research on the blood.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670618">
    <title>al-Durr al-manẓūm. -- 1731 or 2.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Variant title in manuscript: Naẓm farāʾiḍ Multaqá al-abḥur.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, in brown, with flap.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">With: 6 other titles.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670642">
    <title>[Kitāb fī al-farāʾiḍ]. -- 1828 or 9.</title>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, in brown, with flap.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Followed by an untitled 2-page treatise on same subject; ends abruptly.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Last 3 leaves comprised of notes.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">With: 6 other titles.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670725">
    <title>al-ʻArūḍ al-Andalusī. -- [17--].</title>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Islamic binding, in brown, with flap.</note>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">A few pages of notes precede and follow main text.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">With: 6 other titles.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670732">
    <title>Ye Sette of Odd Volumes : "Idler" collection : typescript.</title>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Looseleaf.</note>
    <note type="a" review="n" reviewer="wn">Title from first page.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670810">
    <title>Book of accounts, 1793-1803.</title>
    <note type="aw" review="n" reviewer="wn">Caption title; the 22 p. at end contain the doctor's handwritten comments on some patients tended during 1793-95.</note>
    <note type="o" review="y" reviewer="wn">Photocopy by Thomas G. Falco (then assistant historical librarian, Yale medical historical library) at New Haven, Conn., 1974; from original owned by Beekman C. Cannon, Master of Yale's Jonathan Edwards College. Yale med copy is 21 leaves, and 28 cm.</note>
    <note type="o" review="n" reviewer="wn">Each photocopied leaf has 2 pages of text.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670835">
    <title>Excelsior diary : Columbian edition, 1893 / [signed in ink on title page: Geo. W. Vansint].</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Diary includes a blank page for each date, printed almanac and calendar, and pages for accounts.</note>
    <note type="aw" review="n" reviewer="wn">Although this is obviously a physician's book, detailing his practice in New York City, I can find no listing of Vansint in Polk's, AMA, NUC, New York Acad., or Worldcat directories.</note>
    <note type="ow" review="y" reviewer="wn">Manuscript, written in ink on lined paper, is notebook, diary, and account book; it was donated to Yale Med by Charles Anchie in November, 1966.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="3670836">
    <title>Account book, 1862-1870.</title>
    <note type="w" review="n" reviewer="wn">Includes patient information concerning the doctor's practice in New Haven, Conn.</note>
  </record>
</records>