<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<records path="unclassified_as_of_2025-12-17/by_format/XML/zoe_unclassified.xml">
  <record bib="13193565">
    <title>[Praises of Saint Mary, Blessed Virgin, and gate of light].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript in red and black, one column, 14 lines per page. F.1rv and f.58rv appear to be leaves (a bifolium?) discarded from another manuscript, covered with pen trials.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Wooden boards, four chain stitches; one column; 14 lines per page.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">F. 57r: Prayer by one Gabra Selassie to Mary to “keep me in body and soul.” A secondary hand adds the name Gabra Maryam.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13193592">
    <title>[Prayer of Our Lady Mary at Golgotha, mystagogia, sword of divinity, and bandlet of righteousness].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In red and black, bound in leather between wooden boards, one column, 13-14 lines per page. Flyleaves contain images of Mary, Jesus, and Michael. Some decorative headpieces. Some marginalia.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">F. 1r: Note: Edited by ግዛቸው ወልዴ ነው, written in an untrained hand; F. 4r mentions the owner, ወልደ ሚካኤል; Blank: ii v, iii rv. 53v.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Illuminations: F. 1v: Madonna and Child, flanked by the angels Gabriel and Michael; F. 2r: Angel with drawn sword and scabbard.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13193823">
    <title>[Computus of Demetrius of Alexandria].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In red and black ink, 3 columns, 24 to 29 lines per page. Flyleaves are sown together. Detailed decorative headpieces throughout. Some sections intentionally blotted out (e.g. f. 10). Some marginalia. Some tears and holes sewn back together. F. 48ff. contain numerical, calendrical, and astronomical charts.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13193832">
    <title>[Bandlet of righteousness].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript in black and red ink. First page contains a decorative cross. Substantial damage to some pages. A description of the object is given: "The little scroll belongs to the common literature of Lefafa sedq (bandlet of truth), principally used for burial with the deceased. That is, prayers of Mary, here the part called the Mashafa heywat (book of life). It is represented by innumerable copies in libraries and elsewhere."</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13193842">
    <title>[Funeral ritual].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In black and red ink, bound between wooden covers with four chain stitches, two columns, 18-20 lines per page.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Some decorative headpieces. Some graffiti in flyleaves. Handwritten note (20th century) between f. 3 and f. 4: "apparently liturgy (prayers [selot], lessons from the gospels, etc.)". The Beinecke's cover for the book reads "Lectionary," which conflicts with the internal note's claims concerning the text.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">F. 120v: Note of ownership: the name of the owner has been erased. After a set of lines creating a unit division is a list of names of family members and also of the scribe, ዜና ገብርኤል እልፍዮስ.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13193845">
    <title>[Psalter, followed by canticles, Song of Songs, praises of Mary, and gate of light].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Half bound with leather between wooden boards, the front board being broken and stitched; four chain stitches. One column (ff. 1r-148r), two columns (ff. 149r-167v). In red and black ink.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Flyleaf contains depiction of royal figure with a harp (David?) and other figures. Some decorative headpieces, including images of houses and pyramids(?). f. 43 contains a depiction of St. George and the Dragon. Some holes and tears sewn back together. Final section of book contains a narrative including Mary. f. 148 contains a depiction of a woman (Mary?) carrying a cross, a man carrying two vessels, and two ghostly figures floating above.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Illuminations: F. ii v: David playing his harp (the scene is depicted with David’s body in profile, though his face shows both eyes), before him (right) are three people; One (at the bottom) lies prostrate and holds shield and rifle; A second stands before David with a Psalter in hand; Above, a third holds a sword over his shoulder; A crude hand has written, “This Psalter belongs to ቄስ መሬ;” F. 43v: Saint George and the Dragon, caption: ቅዱስ ጊዮር[ጊ]ስ; F. 148v: Saint Mary, (right) holding hand cross, before Saint Ephrem(?) (left) also holding objects in his hands, above two angels hover over Mary.</note>
    <note num="4" type="">F. ii: stamp of the Yale University Library; F. 162r mentions the scribe (ጸሐፊሁ), ኃይለ [the second name is erased]; Inside back cover: owner plate of the Yale University Library: Gift of Thomas Ewart Marston; Blank: Ff. irv, 168rv, 169v; F. 167v: record: Scribal note of completion: “the end of the Dawit on Tahsas 11 in the peace of God.”</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13194240">
    <title>[Psalter, calendar, biblical canticles, Song of Songs, praises of Mary, and gate of light].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In black and red ink. Half bound with leather, between wooden boards, the front one of which is broken and stitched. Four chain stitches, one column (ff. 5r-155r), two columns (ff. 155v-169v). Substantial marginalia. Some later editorial decorations added in a crayon-like substance. Some lacunae have been patched and rewritten. Some holes and tears have been sewn back together.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">F. 1r: text: pen trial; F. 1v: text: Calendar, in an 18th century hand; F. 2r–3v, upper: text, in a 19th century hand; F. 3v, lower and 4r, lower: text, in a 20th century hand; F. 4v: text: calendar; F. 151r, bottom margin: note of secondary ownership, ገብረ ጊዎርጊስ, written in a later hand.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13194310">
    <title>[Canticle of the flower, lamentations of the Virgin, image of Mary, and image of the Trinity].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In red and black ink. One column, 13-14 lines per page.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">The flyleaf contains a depiction of four figures (perhaps including Mary and Jesus?). Some crayon-like headpieces in purple, orange, and green. f. 44 contains later Ethiopic additions written in pen. Minimal marginalia. The final flyleaves contain graffiti crosses and pencil writing.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Illuminations : F. 2v: Madonna and Child with the Angels Mika’el and Gabri’el behind; Ff. 90v and 91r: drawings of the fraction of the host.</note>
    <note num="4" type="">Notes: F. 3r mentions an owner, ኃይለ ማርያም; Blank: 90r; F. 91v: Record dated in 1948, Tahsas 28, regarding the sale of the book of Canticle of the Flower for 6 birr, witnesses are listed; at the end, “to not deny the selling of the book, I put my fingerprint.” There are fingerprints and signatures of the parties. “If I change my word, may Haile Selassie die".</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13194992">
    <title>[Psalter, biblical canticles, Song of Songs, praises of Mary, and gate of light].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In red and black ink. Bound between wooden boards with four chain stitches. One column (ff. 3r-127r); two columns (ff. 127v-140r), 26-27 lines per page.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">f. 1 is upside down, yet the graffiti is correctly oriented. Ethiopic graffiti in the flyleaf (f. 2). Some marginalia and penciled-in decorations. Sections (?) are numerated in the margins in pencil. Some holes and tears sewn back together.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">F. 2v: Note of ownership; F. 138r: prayers for the owner and others.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13195045">
    <title>[Psalter, biblical canticles, Song of Songs, praises of Mary, and gate of light].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Leather bound between wooden boards with four chain stitchees. One column (ff. 1r-168v); two columns (ff. 169r-184v), 19 lines per page. In red and black ink.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Some marginalia. Numeration on the top margins of some pages (to count quires?). Some holes and tears sewn back together. Some pages excised before modern numeration. Occasional symbols in body of text.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13195060">
    <title>[Mawaśʻet and zemāré chants].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In black and red ink. Bound between wooden boards, with four chain stitches, one column, 16-20 lines per page. Some holes and tears sewn back together. Occasional pages of different sizes throughout.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13195067">
    <title>[Prayer of Our Lady Mary at Golgotha, absolution of the Son, collection of prayers].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Ff. 1v and 10r mention the owner, ገብራ ወልደ ጻድቅ, [female]; f. 9r mentions another owner, ሐዋዘ ብርሃን, [male]; Ff. 1r, 10v–14r are blank.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">In red and black ink, single quire from a book, with no covers, two columns, 23-28 lines per page.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13195075">
    <title>[Magic scroll of spiritual healing].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Scroll on parchment, one column. Tears in parchment sewn back together. Illustration of two figures carrying a large cross and a seraphic figure. Leather strap on the top of the scroll.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">The owner is never mentioned.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13195325">
    <title>[Miracles of Mary].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Leather bound between wooden boards with four chain stitches. In black and red ink. Three columns, 26-27 lines per page. There is fine cloth between the turndowns on the inside back cover.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Detailed illustrations in the first flyleaves, depicting Mary, among many other human and angelic figures. Decorative headpieces throughout. Some marginalia. Numerical markings at the beginning of each quire. Various illuminated pages throughout the text depicting the life and miracles of Mary.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">1868-1913 (ff. 5r and passim) mention Emperor Menilek, 1868–1913; and f. 195v mentions Ras Mikael of Wollo, 1850–1918); the harags also indicate production in the Menilek scriptorium.</note>
    <note num="4" type="">1. The last of the miracles (ff. 193v–195v) is written in a different hand and dated in the time of “Our King Mika’el,” i.e., Ras Mikael of Wollo, 1850–1918.; 2. Inside cover contains the ownership plate of Yale University Library, Gift of Laurence and Cora Witten; 3. f. ir: written in the upper left corner [12210]; 4. Ff. i v–ii r, iii v, and 69r are blank.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13215294">
    <title>Order authorizing payment to Jonathan Forward for transporting convicts to the American plantations : manuscript / R. Walpole ; Charels Turner ; Richard Edgecombe.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In brown ink on cream laid paper.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13216917">
    <title>[Magic scroll of spiritual healing].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Scroll on parchment, two columns, black and red ink.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">The scroll was made for ወለተ ሩፋኤል.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217147">
    <title>[Synaxarium].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Ordered by Abba Mikaʼel and Abba Yohannes.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Volumes in wooden boards, with four chain stitches, three columns, 34-38 lines per page, in red and black ink.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">V.1: Synaxarium for the first part of the year: F. 1r mentions the ones who ordered the book: Abba Mika’el, whose country is አትሪብ (in Egypt?), Abba Yohannes, whose country is ቡርልስ. F. 163v contains further information about the book; the two volumes of the Synaxarium were purchased by ገብረ ማርያም, with his own money for two ወቂት; the record also mentions other books he bought; thereafter, the record (continuing on f. 165r) mentions a list of purchased books owned by the church, 20 books in all, as well other church utensils and priestly garments, crosses; another record lists books given by other people with a curse on anyone who steals or erases; a final record, written in a different hand, lists more books and materials given to the church; f. 164v contains the name plate of Yale University Library, the Edwin J. Beinecke Fund</note>
    <note num="4" type="">V.2: Synaxarium for the second part of the year: 1868–1913 (f. 61v mentions Emperor Menilek,1868–1913, and Governor Ras Hailu,1868–1950); f. 1r mentions the ones who ordered the book: Abba Mika’el, whose country is አትሪብ (in Egypt?), Abba Yohannes, whose country is ቡርልስ. 1. f. i r: owner plate: Yale University Library; The Edwin J. Beinecke Fund; 2. f. i v: Pen trial, written in trained hand; 3. f. ii r: An incomplete record, mentioning the dates Genbot 5, and 19, written in an untrained hand; 4. f. ii r, bottom: another incomplete record mentioning Miyazia 25 and 26, Sane 17 and Arias, the heretic, written in an untrained hand; 5. ff. 2v and 194v are blank. F. 44r has the name ወልደ ሰንባት, written into the blank, written in a different hand; f. 61v has a note of ownership in a different hand: This book belongs to the church, ዋሻ ሚካኤል during the time of Emperor Menilek (1868–1913) and Governor (Ras) Hailu (1858–1950), and Qängazmač Alemu, and church manager ቄሰ ገበዝ ተገኝ, and Märigeta ዛይህመ, church scholar, in the year of Evangelist Saint John, it was purchased. ቄሰ ገበዝ ተገኝ, whose baptismal name is ወልደ ተንሣኤ, is the one bought it as the property of the church ዋሻ ሚካኤል; it appears that the hand changes half way through f. 86v.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217202">
    <title>[Missal].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">1721–1726 (f. 1r mentions the 7,221st year of creation [=1721], and “the month of February (Yakatit) ... in the time of our King, Bakafa [1721–1730]; f. 19v mentions Abba Petros = Peter VI, 1718–1726, and Abba Krestodolu III, 1720–1735; the overlap between the three dates—king, Coptic Patriarch, and Ethiopian Abuna—is 1721–1726); the colophon itself mentions the eighth year of Bakafa’s reign, i.e., 1729.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Introductory colophon to the manuscript: "In the name of the Father and Son and Holy Spirit, one God. How we remember the calculation of the year of our Lord Jesus Christ since we are in the year of Matthew the Evangelist, may He keep us until the year of Mark (the Evangelist), in the 7,221st year of creation [=1721], since there is no epact for [the ringing of] its bell, the month of February (Yakatit), the fourth day and seventh night, in the time of our King, Bakafa [1721-1730], in the eighth year after he became king, this book was written." [Text is damaged.]</note>
    <note num="3" type="">F. 19v mentions Abba Petros = Peter VI, 1718–1726, and Abba Krestodolu III, 1720–1735. The overlap between the three dates (King and Coptic Patriarch and Ethiopian Abuna) is 1721–1726.</note>
    <note num="4" type="">In wooden boards, with four chain stitches, leather bound, two columns, 22-23 lines per page, black and red ink. Fine fabric is visible between the pastedowns of the front and back covers. Double slip mahdar.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217324">
    <title>[Code of kings].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Leather bound, perhaps in the West.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">19th century (the note in the front suggests early-19th century when Henry Salt was in Adwa).</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Notes: 1. f. i r(ecto): “[..lnyed?] to Henry Salt. Sent to him from Adwa by Nathaniel Pierce;” Inside front cover has an ownership plate of Yale University Library, gift of Thomas Ewart Marston, Yale [1927 (out of focus)]; f. 297v: note of completion and gifting of the book.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217372">
    <title>[150 Psalms of David].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Note of content: "Psalms of David, translated into Tigrê by Debtera Matheos at Adoa. Unrevised," with comments nearby in a different hand: "Henry Salt's writing; Sent to him from Adwa by Nathaniel Pearce."</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Leather bound, one column, 19 lines, running header.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Foliated in the upper right recto.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217422">
    <title>[Acts of the Apostles, Epistles, and Revelation].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Note of content: "Acts, Epistles &amp; Revelation, translated by Debtera Matheos into Tigrê. Unrevised", with comments nearby in a different hand: "Henry Salt's writing; Sent to him from Adwa by Nathaniel Pearce".</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Leather bound, one column, 19-20 lines, running header.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Foliated in the upper right recto.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13217753">
    <title>[The story of Mary and Ephrem and the composition of the Praises of Mary, gate of light, book of Mohammad Grañ, and image of Saint George zaSalédā Mogas].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">: Notes: 1. F. ii r(ecto): A list of names of a leading judge and priest of the region of ዐፎሊ ምድር; there follows at least three more names of people; the names appear to be of Oromo people; 2. ff. 6r, 12v and passim, mention an owner ቅብዓ ሥላሲ. 3. f. 58r mentions another owner(?), ወልደ ማርያም; 4. f. 19r mentions the scribe, ገብረ ኪዳን; 5. frame 109v mention later owners(?) or family members, written in a later hand: ገብረ ማርያም, ወልደ ማርያም, ወልዳ ኢየሱስ.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">With leather case.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">One of the scribes was Gabre Kidān.</note>
    <note num="4" type="">Between wooden boards, with four chain stitches, one column, 13 lines per page, in black and red ink.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13231335">
    <title>Peter Delmé Esqr. bill from Edward Peirce, December 1764 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Devised title. Docket title on verso: 15th Dect. 1764 Edwd. Pierce for thatching at Posbrooks pd. £5:17:2.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13234595">
    <title>19 famous recipes.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Written in black ink, with headings in red.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13278651">
    <title>A perspective view of Dilston Hall, once the seat of the unfortunate James, Earl of Derwent-Water [graphic] / T. Oliver delin. ; Spilsbury sculp., Russel-Court, London.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Title engraved above image.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Plate signed below image.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Verses below image begin: How mournful feeble nature's tone, when Dilston-Hall appears ...</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13290057">
    <title>Spotter Card Trick.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Card game with 6 playing cards 5 of which are double playing cards. Ace of Club on all cards. 5 cards are 3, 4, and 5 of spades and 4 and 5 of clubs.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">"Six cards including one Ace of Clubs are openly shown. The six cards are laid in a row. When one is chosen it is always the Ace."</note>
    <note num="3" type="">"Full instructions and complete patter are included."</note>
    <note num="4" type="">"Made in England."</note>
    <note num="5" type="">"No. 67."</note>
    <note num="6" type="">"E &amp; S. Copyight."</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13290122">
    <title>Merry Widow Hanky : a laugh on the girls.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">"The girls get curious about the ruffles on the Handkerchief showing from your pocket. They think you have other sweethearts but when they investigate the hanky, AH! it is not a Handkerchief at all but something else, indeed!! Fold the hanky so that the lace protrudes frm the pocket--it won't take long for the fun to start."</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Handkerchief, unfolded, is in the shape of a pair of lavender lace trimmed ladies underwear with the poem printed on them: Short but Sweet. Mary had some little pants/Too short were they to show/But everywhere that Mary went/The pants were sure to go. Accompanied by printed paper envelope.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13290842">
    <title>Chevalier d'Eon letter to Counsellor Pigott regarding dispute over lease of a house in London, 1798 March 29 : autograph manuscript signed.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">"Londres 29 mars 1798"--Page 1.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Final page blank.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Letter is folded at fore edge to fit into the book in which it is bound.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13330158">
    <title>John Boyle Orrery letter, to Messrs. Dodsley, [not before 1754] : manuscript / Corke.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Date based on beginning of partnership of Robert and James Dodsley</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Dodsley spelled "Dodseley" in the address.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13399445">
    <title>George H. Thomas letter, Louisville, Kentucky, to George Pearson Buell, Lynchburg, Virginia, 1867 May 1 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript copy, unsigned, from Thomas's letterbook, possibly in an unidentified secretary's hand.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13473253">
    <title>Harry Grover account book, 1783 July 18-1786 October 14 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript title in ink on front board: No. 1, Account book 18th July 1783 ending 14th October 1786.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Contemporary vellum front board; rebacked, with matching back board.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13495441">
    <title>Francis M. Emerson letter, Canon Creek, California, to Susan Hunt Emerson, 1854 November 20 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13495661">
    <title>J. J. Zimmerman letter, La Grange, California, to Franklin A. Hinds, Portland, Oregon, 1865 September 8 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13500706">
    <title>Translation of a report by Álvaro de Bazan, marquês de Santa Cruz, on the defense of Spain and the West Indies from Sir Francis Drake : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Provenance: Henry Stevens; Sir Thomas Phillipps; Paul Mellon.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13533781">
    <title>880-02 Tōdaiji-gire : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Housed in a box inscribed by Yukio Fukuda.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Displayed at "Irodorareta kami ryōshi sōshoku," an exhibit at the Tokugawa Museum in 2001.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">"Sanbō ekotoba, gekan, Sōbō, shigatsu, dai 17 , Taianji no daihanyae" no dankan.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13535896">
    <title>Indictment of Claude-Louis-François Régnier, comte de Guerchy for conspiring to assassinate Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d'Eon : manuscript fragment.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Indictment alleges that on October 31 in the fourth year of the reign of George III (that is, 1763), the comte de Guerchy attempted to hire Peter Henry Treyssac de Vergy to assassinate d'Eon.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Includes at end a separate certification of authenticity written in French by d'Eon, at London, dated 18 September 1767.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Paginated 147-148.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13556465">
    <title>Corrine Nishimura autograph album : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Disbound by a former owner.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13558801">
    <title>Indenture placing William Spill into the service of William Beales, broad weaver.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">"This indenture witnesseth that [William Spill], one of the poor [boys] of the charity-school of [the parish of Wotton Underedge in the County of Gloucester to the one part] doth put h[im]self apprentice to [William Beales of the parish of Wotton Underedge aforesd. broad weaver of the other part] to learn h[is] art, and with h[im] after the manner of an apprentice to serve from the day of the date hereof, unto the full end and term of [seven] years ... And the said M[aster], (in consideration of the sum of [three] pounds paid to [him] ... ) ... shall teach and instruct, or cause to be taught and instructed, finding unto his said apprentice, meat drink apparel, lodging, washing, and all other necessaries ... In witness thereof, the parties above named to these indentures interchangeably have put their hands and seals the [eighth] day of [April], Anno Dom. 17[28] ... "</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Additional provision written in manuscript, in the margin: "And also shall &amp; will during the said term give and deliver unto his said apprentice six pence a quarter in money every quarter in every year during the said term; and at the end of the sd. term shall &amp; will give and deliver unto his sd. apprentice one new suit of apparel."</note>
    <note num="3" type="">"Sealed and delivered (being first duly stamp'd) in the presence of us, [Thomas Bisigar, John Cooke]"</note>
    <note num="4" type="">At the head of the indenture is an engraved allegorical triptych. The center panel features a depiction of George III. At left, a young female student stands in front of "the Pillar of Faith" and bears a sign reading "And we as mothers of our Israel." At right, a young male student stands in front of "the Gate of Life" and bears a sign reading "In cause of Church &amp; State may we Excell."</note>
    <note num="5" type="">Includes a blind-embossed tax stamp.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13577473">
    <title>Charles Cauchon de Maupas letter, Hinchingbrooke House, to Nicholas de Neufville, marquis de Villeroi, 1603 May 8 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Hinchingbrooke House appears as "Finchinbrook" in the letter.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Integral address panel directed to "Monsieur monsieur de Villeroy" with remains of a red wax seal.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13596622">
    <title>Account book relating to railroad construction in Morrisania, New York : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Bookseller's ticket: H. &amp; S. Raynor, 76 Bowery, New York.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13604935">
    <title>Henry Seymour daybook : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Unidentified account book fragments from circa 1803-1807 used as binding paste-downs.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13614323">
    <title>Letter : No. 36 Windmill Street Rathbone Place, to Richard Bull, 1784 December 18.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Tipped in at page 240 of Richard Bull's copiously extra-illustrated copy of: Walpole, H. A description of the villa of Mr. Horace Walpole. Strawberry Hill : Printed by Thomas Kirgate, 1784. See Hazen, A.T. Bibliography of the Strawberry Hill Press (1973 ed.), no. 30, copy 13.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13618347">
    <title>Lace sample book.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">In "Patent Self Binder" (no. 15868) made by Priestley &amp; Swann, Ltd., Nottingham. The firm of Priestly &amp; Swann was active from ca. 1895 until well into the 20th century.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13629180">
    <title>Joseph Frothingham letter, Sacramento, California, to Elizabeth Ann Frothingham, Brooklyn, New York, 1850 April 1 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13640137">
    <title>James E. Wisner letter, Lisbon, North Dakota, to an unidentified recipient, 1891 June 22 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">No. 1 of 2 items housed together.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13642021">
    <title>Parry commonplace book : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Contemporary full paneled calf.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13665718">
    <title>880-01 Otorika tomegaki, undated.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Yale bookplate date: 1907.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">On double leaves, traditional East Asian binding style (fukurotoji).</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13668225">
    <title>A. Decker diary : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Diary is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13673208">
    <title>Records of livestock brands in Taos County and Union County, New Mexico : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Volume 1: Taos County, 1853-1878. Volume 2: Taos County, 1879-1886. Volume 3: Taos County, 1873-1899, and Union County, circa 1873-1899, with later manuscript additions dated 1907-1910.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13673437">
    <title>Promissory note issued to John Fellowes : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Laid in to a larger sheet of paper.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13675125">
    <title>Letter, Nacogdoches, Texas, to Stephen F. Austin, 1831 January 3 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed English translation made by an unidentified translator.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Misdated as 1830 January 3, but letter was written after the Mexican law of April 6, 1830.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13757503">
    <title>Passports of George Treherne Thomas.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Both passports are in contemporary wallet style bindings, with flaps intact. Both bear the gilt-stamped name of George Treherne Thomas.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13772777">
    <title>L'Orfeo [microform] : tragicomedia per musica.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript of the libretto by Francesco Buti to the opera by Luigi Rossi.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13824317">
    <title>Amos Mix letter, Knox County, Ohio, to David Frost, Waterbury, Connecticut,  1811 December 18 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is dated 1811 December 18, with an autograph postscript by Mix dated 1812 July 23.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13825130">
    <title>The Oxford declarations.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript described in John Griffiths' manscript table of contents as "abstracts and remarks on the number of signatures to the three declarations" of the University of Oxford in 1834.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Catpion title.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">"About 2670 persons were entitled to sign the three declarations. Of these a large number, say 170, were either abroad or ill or could not be found. There remain as dispentients about 485 : so that the opponents of the bill outnumbered its supporters in a greater ratio than that of four to one"--Page 1.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13831403">
    <title>Korrespondenzen italienische Kardinäle und anderer Personen, besonders italiener, an Herzog Johann Friedrich.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letters from Johann Friedrich's Italian correspondents between the years 1667-1679. Items of musical importance include letters of Francesco Maria Massi (210 letters, 1669-1676), Pietro Dolfino (58 letters, 1669-1678), Antonio Sartorio (18 letters, 1672-1679), and Nicolò Bérégan (27 letters, 1669-1678).</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Detailed description in: Nel theatro di tutta l'Europa : Venetian-Hanoverian patronage in 17th-century Europe / Vassilis Vavoulis. Lucca : Libreria musicale italiana, c2010.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13839505">
    <title>R. D. Mussey letter, Washington, D.C., to Nathaniel Prentiss Banks, 1866 March 21 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13848416">
    <title>Charles Nichols letter, Fort Steilacoom, Washington, to William R. Thomas, 1861 May 9 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a manuscript transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13848809">
    <title>Edward Otho Cresap Ord letter to an unidentified recipient, 1849 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter is accompanied by a typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13860833">
    <title>Scrapbook of newspaper clippings from Liverpool newspapers concerning the trial of Queen Caroline : printed text.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Some clippings folded, others bound in; contemporary half roan morocco binding.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13876265">
    <title>Sample books for printed cotton fabrics manufactured by Koechlin &amp; Frères.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">For more information on the dyeing of printed fabrics in general, and for mention of Koechlin dyes in particular, see: Greene, Susan W. Wearable prints, 1760-1860: history, materials, and mechanics. Kent, Ohio: The Kent State University Press, 2014. For a brief history of the Koechlin firm, see: Smith, Michael Stephen. The emergence of modern business enterprise in France, 1800-1930. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 2006 (pages 139-140).</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Both volumes are bound in contemporary brown cloth.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13876929">
    <title>J. Russell Hodge diary : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Diary is accompanied by a partial typed transcription made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13888969">
    <title>[Ethiopian scroll of spiritual healing].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Scroll on parchment, one column, single-line borders, rubricated for the start of new prayers and for the names of the saints and for the name(s) of the owner(s).</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Probably missing a third strip of parchment that would have carried final prayers and a third illumination.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13889076">
    <title>[Folio from Eusebian canon table in a 15th century four Gospels manuscript].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Folio on parchment. This folio contains the first two canon tables, one on recto, one on verso.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Eleven (depending on how the tables are organized) additional canon tables are not present with this copy.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13895121">
    <title>Jeu doigts.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Original collage in the form of a board game on 2 attached pieces of cardboard consisting of 63 rectangles (3 of them unnumbered) 58 x 54 mm and another cut-out image numbered 63 of Jesus with halo and his left arm raised. The image of Jesus overlaps the final rectangle. The rectangles are photos, most of them of exposed parts of female anatomy. In the center of the board is manuscript text "Règle du jeu-doigts. On y jouera comme au 'jeu de l'oie' ordinaire ..." signed: gaudryj 1964. The title is stenciled on front panel when folded. There is a partially erased presentation inscription signed "Gaudry 64" beneath title.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13909509">
    <title>Excerpts from William Burkitt's Expository notes.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">A note in a much later hand at the front of the album attributes the manuscript (presumably the copied text and the original drawings) to Mary Smith of Cropwell Butler, Nottinghamshire. The basis of this attribution is unclear.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">In general text and illustration appear on one side of a leaf, usually on facing pages.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Leaves of the album are watermarked 1846.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13927147">
    <title>Charles N. Morris letters, 1869 February 17-1882 December 6.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letters accompanied by typescript transcriptions by an unidentified individual.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="13974316">
    <title>Edward DeLevan Barker diary, 1858 August 16-1860 April 1.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Diary accompanied by partial typed transcript made by an unidentified transcriber.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Diary accompanied by a photocopy.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14028764">
    <title>Thomas Gainsborough letter to Elizabeth Rasse.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Written in black ink.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">The sheet was previously folded, with small remnants of a wax seal.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14043117">
    <title>Seed lien record : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Title taken from spine.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14066827">
    <title>Letter from Jno. H. Teitlebaum, East Las Vegas, New Mexico, to Messrs J. W. Rulifson Bro., Lincoln, Nebraska, March 20, 1889 : autograph manuscript, signed.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Letter written on stationery with lithographed letterhead "Established in 1880. Office of Jno. H Teitlebaum, mortgage, loan and real estate broker ... East Las Vegas, N.M." offering for sale confirmed and patented land at government price in Las Vegas, New Mexico.</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Two punch holes through each sheet with slight damage to letterhead.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14077969">
    <title>Thomas Edwards letter to Sir Dudley North, Clifford's Inn, London, 1683 November 15 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Docket, probably in the hand of Sir Dudley North: "15 Nov. 1683. Mr. Edwards."</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Integral address panel. Cover side contains an example of the first English Penny Post stamp: a triangle bearing the words "Payd peny post" surrounding a capital "T," adjacent to the time stamp "p/af/5" (St. Paul's).</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14112789">
    <title>Assignment of household goods from Bedingfeild Heigham to Thomas White, 1708 May 11 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Docket: "Assignment of Household goods &amp;c. from B. Heigham to Thomas White."</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Document signed: "B. Heigham." Signature followed by red wax seal.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Document signed by two witnesses: "Owen Lloyd" and "Joshua Miles."</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14118322">
    <title>Conveyance between Roger Sadler and William Cecil, Lord Burghley, 1586/1587 January 27 : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Dated at the end of the main text: "vicesimo septimo die Januarii Anno regni d[omi]na n[ost]r[a] Elizabeth...vicesimo nono."</note>
    <note num="2" type="">Docketed on verso in two later hands, partially effaced.</note>
    <note num="3" type="">Signatures and/or marks of eight witnesses on verso, including the signature of Barnard Dewhurst.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14472872">
    <title>Worke done for the Kings most excellent maiestie : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Docketed in a contemporary hand: "Ralph Roades rainmaker his Bill. 18 Apr 1662."</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14498801">
    <title>The doctrine of the series, or, Musical rhythm based on common arithmetic : with tables / by Joseph Gersbach ; prepared &amp; published from a fragment left by the author by Anton Gersbach.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Manuscript.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14504752">
    <title>[Collection of newspaper clippings of advertisements for theater, performances, and recently published books].</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Collection title devised by cataloger.</note>
  </record>
  <record bib="14508679">
    <title>Muster-in roll of Frank North's company, of Pawnee Scouts, called into the service of the United States : manuscript.</title>
    <note num="1" type="">Title taken from first page.</note>
  </record>
</records>